Contact

+12105575391 (Mobile) randy@signatureagility.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ randysmithagilecoach (LinkedIn) signatureagile.com/ (Company)

Top Skills

Scrum

Testing

Agile Methodologies

Languages

German (Elementary)

Certifications

ITIL v2 Foundation

ICP - Business Agility Foundations

Publications

5 Tips for Leading a Great Inspect & Adapt Workshop

Pitching PI Objectives to the Sharks

Webinar - Real Agile Transformations (Just add Scrum and SAFe?)

My Stakeholder Just Dropped a New, Shiny Object on Me! Now What?

10 Teaching Tips for Your First SAFe® Classes

Patents

Software patch selection tool

Randy Smith

SPCT & Enterprise Transformation Coach

United States

Summary

Agility made real, understandable and approachable. Getting results with agility doesn't have to be theoretical or hard. I bring real-life experience, tell (anonymized) stories, and break it down so you can get it without the struggle. I offer choices, good practices, and advice, not dogma.

Sectors:

Typically in medium to large companies. I've worked in Tech, Manufacturing, Aerospace, Shipping, Financial, and Medical/Pharma firms.

Roles:

I've been an IT professional for more than 25 years now. I've filled a broad variety of roles including developer, tester, support, test management, release management, etc. My first "agile" team was back in 1998.

Experience

Engaged Agility
SPCT & Enterprise Coach
September 2022 - Present (2 years 5 months)
United States

Signature Agility, LLC Principal Consultant June 2019 - Present (5 years 8 months)

United States

Bringing my signature blend of business agility knowledge and skills to your unique transformation

Teksystems LLC SPCT & Enterprise Transformation Coach September 2020 - September 2022 (2 years 1 month)

Page 1 of 4

United States

- Helping grow better engagements and better coaches
- Helping drive out Agile PMO (APMO) and Lean-Agile Center of Excellence

Temenos+Agility
SPCT & Enterprise Transformation Coach
January 2020 - September 2020 (9 months)
Greater Seattle Area

Helping clients create business agility by:

- Co-leading client organizational design and development efforts, including their agile transformations, by helping them create their transformation roadmap, then guiding them through executing it.
- Helping grow the Agile Program Management Office (APMO) and Lean-Agile Center of Excellent (LACE)
- Developing leaders (VPs, Directors, and Managers) into lean / agile thinkers who make workplaces better and remove waste.
- Coaching the across-the-board roll-out of lean portfolio management, as well as divisional portfolio rollouts.
- Crafting Business and IT agile teams into value-aligned programs delivering IT-based and non-IT-based solutions.
- Building client coaching teams by identifying skill and experience needs, then coaching and mentoring them to become coaches their organizations valued and were proud of.
- Matching client areas with coaches based on and area/coach fit.

ICON Agility Services
SPCT, Transformation Coach
July 2018 - January 2020 (1 year 7 months)
Madison, Wisconsin Area

Led medium-to-large organizations through lean / agile adoption and transformation across many programs in medium-to-large organizations, helping them deliver real value. Building agile leaders, programs, and coaches by:

- Co-leading agile transformations with the client by creating their transformation roadmap, then guiding them through executing it.
- Developing leaders (VPs, Directors, and Managers) into lean / agile thinkers who make workplaces better and remove waste.

- Coaching the across-the-board roll-out of lean portfolio management, as well as divisional portfolio rollouts.
- Crafting Business and IT agile teams into value-aligned programs delivering IT-based and non-IT-based solutions.
- Building client coaching teams in a Lean-Agile Center of Excellence by identifying skill and experience needs, then coaching and mentoring them to become coaches their organizations valued and were proud of.
- Matching client areas with coaches based on and area/coach fit.

SolutionsIQ (Acquired by Accenture)
Sr. Agile Coach & Trainer, Sr Manager
February 2015 - July 2018 (3 years 6 months)

Greater Denver Area

Helped organizations in many industries start down the path toward delivering the value their customers needed.

- Helped dozens of IT and non-IT teams start and continuously improve using an agile mindset.
- Showed teams of teams how to collaborate and align to create real business value.
- Developed leaders into lean / agile thinkers who make workplaces better and remove waste.
- Taught in large-groups formats, small teams settings, or just one-on-one.

Tools: Scaled Agile Framework (SAFe), Scrum, Kanban, Lean Thinking, Coaching

Hewlett-Packard 17 years 2 months

Agile Coach

February 2014 - February 2015 (1 year 1 month)

Fort Collins, Colorado Area

Formally started coaching Scrum & Scaled Agile Framework (SAFe) at an organizational level! To do that, I:

- Trained and launched six trains in the organizations.
- Coached and mentored a global community of 25+ ScrumMasters and ~12 product owners.
- Used Communities of Practice and cross-cutting Agile Improvement Communities.

• Formally trained more than 300 leaders, product owners, developers, testers, and managers across the planet in Scrum, XP, and SAFe. Informally trained on things like release planning, story mapping, estimating, etc.

ScrumMaster / Sr. ScrumMaster
July 2011 - February 2014 (2 years 8 months)
Fort Collins, Colorado Area

Found my new passion in life as an agilist! I helped one small team adopt scrum practices, like stand-ups, retrospectives, sprint planning, reviews, backlog refinement, etc. As I got better, I helped other teams, eventually branching out to help my global organization get better at Scrum.

Systems / Software Engineer
January 1998 - July 2011 (13 years 7 months)
Various

As a full-stack software developer, I worked on a small team using agile principles as we created software to reduce process time from days to minutes, saving the company millions. We received U.S. patent 6477730 for it. Worked on various other projects and teams, in various roles, including developer, test manager, release manager, software packaging, etc.

Tools: Scrum, Java, Perl, Test Management, Release Management, Continuous Integration (Jenkins)

Education

Graceland University
Bachelor of Science - BS, CIS, Business, Accounting

Colorado State University - Global Campus

Master's Certificate, Research & Decision Making In Organizational

Leadership · (2010)

Agile Coaching Institute

Agile Coaching Institute